Rory Hartong-Redden

Menlo Park, CA | roryhr@gmail.com | Cell: 925.297.9484 | roryhr.github.io | github.com/roryhr

Summary

research scientist, machine learning aka deep learning aka AI, python developer, data scientist, physicist

Skills Summary

Languages: Python, R ML: Neural Networks, Gradient Boosted Machines

Data: SQL, Postgres, HDF5 Dev: Git, Heroku, PyCharm, AWS

Python Tools: Conda, Keras, matplotlib, NumPy, OpenCV, Pandas, scikit-learn, SQLAlchemy

Work Experience

• Allstate Menlo Park, CA

Lead Research Analyst Jul 2015-Present

Working on a secret project (to be published) in the autonomous vehicle and safety space

• Startup.ML San Francisco, CA Machine Learning Fellow Dec 2015-Apr 2016

Developed a FinTech data pipeline for algorithmic currency trading using machine learning

- Lead the integration of an open-source Python backtesting and trading platform
- Research in Reinforcement Learning for autonomous trading
- Harold Washington College

Chicago, IL

Adjunct Faculty

Feb 2015-May 2015

- Presented complex concepts in Astronomy at the level of the general public

Projects

• Master's Thesis

UC Santa Barbara

Krechetnikov Fluid Physics Lab

Dec 2013-Jun 2014

- Incorporated a recent image processing technique for cheap 3D high speed mm-resolution measurement over a surface area of 225 cm² [profilometry repository]
- Bachelor's Thesis: Drop Splash Experiment

Santa Barbara, CA

Krechetnikov Fluid Physics Lab, Dept. of Mechanical Engineering

Jul 2009-Oct 2010

- Published a peer-reviewed article¹ on the experimental and theoretical advances I developed that may have solved a 100-year puzzle in fluid dynamics
- Transient Optical Sky Survey

UC Santa Barbara

Lubin Lab, Dept. of Physics

Sep 2008-Jun 2009

- Image processing with a Matlab/C data pipeline that analyzed 1GB of images taken each night

Education

• University of California, Santa Barbara

MS Mechanical Engineering

Santa Barbara, CA

Dec 2014

• Northwestern University

Evanston, IL

PhD Physics Candidate

Sept 2010-Mar 2012

• University of California, Santa Barbara

Santa Barbara, CA

BS Physics & BS Mechanical Engineering

June 2010

Member: Tau Beta Pi engineering honor society

⁻ Graduated with honor in both degrees, Dean's list 11/12 quarters, GPA: 3.7/4.0

¹Hartong-Redden, R. & Krechetnikov, R. Pattern identification in systems S(1) symmetry. Phys. Rev. E. 2011.